export default {
  id: 'low_1006_4_2a',
  name: '상용한자(4학년-2/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '成', answer: ['이룰 성', 'な(る)、な(す)', 'せい、[じょう]'] },
    { question: '省', answer: ['살필 성', 'はぶ(く)、かえり(みる)', 'せい、しょう'] },
    { question: '巣', answer: ['새집 소', 'す', 'そう'] },
    { question: '焼', answer: ['사를 소', 'や(く)、や(ける)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '笑', answer: ['웃을 소', 'わら(う)、え(む)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '束', answer: ['묶을 속', 'たば', 'そく'] },
    { question: '続', answer: ['이을 속', 'つづ(く)、つづ(ける)', 'ぞく'] },
    { question: '孫', answer: ['손자 손', 'まご', 'そん'] },
    { question: '松', answer: ['소나무 송', 'まつ', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '刷', answer: ['인쇄할 쇄', 'す(る)', 'さつ'] },
    { question: '順', answer: ['순할 순', '순할', 'じゅん'] },
    { question: '試', answer: ['시험할 시', 'ため(す)、こころ(みる)', 'し'] },
    { question: '臣', answer: ['신하 신', '신하', 'しん、じん'] },
    { question: '信', answer: ['믿을 신', '믿을', 'しん'] },
    { question: '失', answer: ['잃을 실', 'うしなう', 'しつ'] },
    { question: '氏', answer: ['성씨 씨', 'うじ', 'し'] },
    { question: '芽', answer: ['싹 아', 'め', 'が'] },
    { question: '児', answer: ['아이 아', '아이', 'じ、[に]'] },
    { question: '案', answer: ['책상 안', '책상', 'あん'] },
    { question: '愛', answer: ['사랑 애', '사랑', 'あい'] },
    { question: '約', answer: ['맺을 약', '맺을', 'やく'] },
    { question: '養', answer: ['기를 양', 'やしな(う)', 'よう'] },
    { question: '漁', answer: ['고기 잡을 어', '고기 잡을', 'ぎょ、りょう'] },
    { question: '億', answer: ['억 억', '억', 'おく'] },
    { question: '然', answer: ['그럴 연', '그럴', 'ぜん、ねん'] },
    { question: '熱', answer: ['더울 열', 'あつ(い)', 'ねつ'] },
    { question: '塩', answer: ['소금 염', 'しお', 'えん'] },
    { question: '英', answer: ['꽃부리 영', '꽃부리', 'えい'] },
    { question: '栄', answer: ['영화 영', 'さか(える)、は(え)、は(える)', 'えい'] },
    { question: '芸', answer: ['재주 예', '재주', 'げい'] },
    { question: '完', answer: ['완전할 완', '완전할', 'かん'] },
    { question: '要', answer: ['요긴할 요', 'かなめ、い(る)', 'よう'] },
    { question: '浴', answer: ['목욕할 욕', 'あ(びる)、あ(びせる)', 'よく'] },
    { question: '勇', answer: ['날랠 용', 'いさ(む)', 'ゆう'] },
    { question: '願', answer: ['원할 원', 'ねが(う)', 'がん'] },
    { question: '位', answer: ['자리 위', 'くらい', 'い'] },
    { question: '囲', answer: ['에워쌀 위', 'かこ(む)、かこ(う)', 'い'] },
    { question: '胃', answer: ['밥통 위', '밥통', 'い'] },
    { question: '泣', answer: ['울 읍', 'な(く)', 'きゅう'] },
    { question: '衣', answer: ['옷 의', 'ころも', 'い'] },
    { question: '議', answer: ['의논할 의', '의논할', 'ぎ'] },
    { question: '以', answer: ['써 이', '써', 'い'] },
    { question: '印', answer: ['도장 인', 'しるし', 'いん'] },
    { question: '昨', answer: ['어제 작', '어제', 'さく'] },
    { question: '残', answer: ['남을 잔', 'のこ(る)、のこ(す)', 'ざん'] },
    { question: '腸', answer: ['창자 장', '창자', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '材', answer: ['재목 재', '재목', 'ざい'] },
    { question: '争', answer: ['다툴 쟁', 'あらそ(う)', 'そう'] },
    { question: '貯', answer: ['쌓을 저', '쌓을', 'ちょ'] },
    { question: '低', answer: ['낮을 저', 'ひく(い)、ひく(める)、ひく(まる)', 'てい'] },
    { question: '底', answer: ['밑 저', 'そこ', 'てい'] },
    { question: '積', answer: ['쌓을 적', 'つ(む)、つ(もる)', 'せき'] },
    { question: '的', answer: ['과녁 적', 'まと', 'てき'] },
    { question: '典', answer: ['법 전', '법', 'てん'] },
    { question: '戦', answer: ['싸움 전', 'いくさ、たたか(う)', 'せん'] },
    { question: '伝', answer: ['전할 전', 'つた(わる)、つた(える)、つた(う)', 'でん'] },
    { question: '折', answer: ['꺾을 절', 'お(る)、お(れる)、おり', 'せつ'] },
    { question: '節', answer: ['마디 절', 'ふし', 'せつ、[せち]'] },
    { question: '静', answer: ['고요할 정', 'しず、しず(か)、しず(まる)、しず(める)', 'せい、[じょう]'] },
    { question: '停', answer: ['머무를 정', '머무를', 'てい'] },
    { question: '兆', answer: ['조 조', 'きざ(す)、きざ(し)', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '照', answer: ['비칠 조', 'て(る)、て(らす)、て(れる)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '卒', answer: ['마칠 졸', '마칠', 'そつ'] },
    { question: '種', answer: ['씨 종', 'たね', 'しゅ'] },
    { question: '周', answer: ['두루 주', 'まわ(り)', 'しゅう'] },
    { question: '仲', answer: ['버금 중', 'なか', 'ちゅう'] },
    { question: '差', answer: ['다를 차', 'さ(す)', 'さ'] },
    { question: '借', answer: ['빌릴 차', 'か(りる)', 'しゃく'] },
    { question: '札', answer: ['편지 찰', 'ふだ', 'さつ'] },
    { question: '察', answer: ['살필 찰', '살필', 'さつ'] },
    { question: '参', answer: ['참여할 참', 'まい(る)', 'さん'] },
    { question: '唱', answer: ['부를 창', 'とな(える)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '倉', answer: ['곳집 창', 'くら', 'そう'] },
    { question: '菜', answer: ['나물 채', 'な', 'さい'] },
    { question: '浅', answer: ['얕을 천', 'あさ(い)', 'せん'] },
    { question: '清', answer: ['맑을 청', 'きよ(い)、きよ(まる)、きよ(める)', 'せい、[しょう]'] },
    { question: '初', answer: ['처음 초', 'はじ(め)、はじ(めて)、はつ、うい、そ(める)', 'しょ'] },
    { question: '最', answer: ['가장 최', 'もっと(も)', 'さい'] },
    { question: '祝', answer: ['빌 축', 'いわ(う)', 'しゅく、[しゅう]'] },
    { question: '側', answer: ['곁 측', 'がわ', 'そく'] },
    { question: '治', answer: ['다스릴 치', 'おさ(める)、おさ(まる)、なお(る)、なお(す)', 'じ、ち'] },
    { question: '置', answer: ['둘 치', 'お(く)', 'ち'] },
    { question: '特', answer: ['특별할 특', '특별할', 'とく'] },
    { question: '敗', answer: ['패할 패', 'やぶ(れる)', 'はい'] },
    { question: '便', answer: ['편할 편', 'たよ(り)', 'べん、びん'] },
    { question: '包', answer: ['쌀 포', 'つつ(む)', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '票', answer: ['표 표', '표', 'ひょう'] },
    { question: '標', answer: ['표할 표', '표할', 'ひょう'] },
    { question: '必', answer: ['반드시 필', 'かなら(ず)', 'ひつ'] },
    { question: '航', answer: ['배 항', '배', 'こう'] },
    { question: '害', answer: ['해할 해', '해할', 'がい'] },
    { question: '験', answer: ['시험 험', '시험', 'けん、[げん]'] },
    { question: '協', answer: ['화합할 협', '화합할', 'きょう'] },
    { question: '型', answer: ['모형 형', 'かた', 'けい'] },
    { question: '好', answer: ['좋을 호', 'この(む)、す(く)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '貨', answer: ['재물 화', '재물', 'か'] },
    { question: '候', answer: ['기후 후', 'そうろう', 'こう'] },
    { question: '訓', answer: ['가르칠 훈', '가르칠', 'くん'] },
    { question: '希', answer: ['바랄 희', '바랄', 'き'] },
    { question: '喜', answer: ['기쁠 희', 'よろこ(ぶ)', 'き'] }
  ]
}
